Sharjeel Faiq

Full Stack Developer - MERN

I'm a MERN Stack Developer who works with multiple frontend and backend languages, technologies, and frameworks and has rich experience in REST APIs, API Integration, version control with Git, GitHub, and GitLab, and website deployment.

EXPERIENCE

1. CrossCom, Islamabad (02/2021 – 06/2023)

Full-stack React JS Developer

• Developed a goal-scoring management system with React JS and Material UI.

2. AcroTech, Islamabad (08/2023 – 11/2023)

Full-stack React JS Developer

- Personalized npm package for views and user interactions.
- Build HR Management System with React and Tailwind CSS.

3. VisualSoft Global LLP (10/2023 – 12/2023)

Full-stack React JS, and WordPress Developer

- Created live streaming and chat using Agora API with React JS.
- Created a company website using WordPress and WPBakery Page Builder.

PROJECTS (clickable - to mention a few)

- MERN + Tailwind CSS E-Commerce Dashboard -
- React JS + Bootstrap 5 Textbotonline →
- React JS + Al-Adhan API Pakistan Prayers →
- React JS + Tailwind CSS YoungStarLabs →
- PHP + Laravel Jotter's Pad →
- WordPress + Elementor Shayan Faiq →
- Custom (HTML, CSS, JS) Power Your Mind →

Click to see more projects...

CONTACT (clickable)

• WhatsApp: +923368856575 →

- Email: sharjeelfaiq816@gmail.com ->
- Address: Gulzar e Quaid, Rawalpindi

WORK PROFILES (clickable)

- Portfolio Website →
- LinkedIn 🗵
- GitHub →
- HackerRank
- StackOverflow -
- Instagram →

REVIEWS

Click to see reviews given to me on Fiverr →

EDUCATION

- BUITEMS: BS Honors Mathematics (2018 2023)
- Punjab College: Pre-Engineering (2015 2018)
- APSACS: Matriculation (2013 2015)

RESPONSIBILITIES & ACHIEVEMENTS

- Integrated and Created APIs to improve the website with more features and interaction.
- Made WordPress websites plugins, child themes, and Beaver Builder modules, and implemented them.
- Used React, Node, Express, Next, and MongoDB for web app development.
- Deployed websites via VPS, SFTP, and GUI on popular hosting platforms.

SKILLS

- HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Typescript
- React JS, Node JS, Express JS
- State Management (e.g. Redux)
- CSS Frameworks
- PHP, Python
- MongoDB, MySQL, Firebase
- WordPress, Webflow
- Git + GitHub + GitLab
- Restful APIs, API Integration
- JavaScript Programming
- Browser Developer Tools
- Command Line Interface
- Website Deployment + AWS